# 下一个节目 开水白菜
The next show is Steamed Chinese Cabbage in Supreme Soup
# 开水白菜的第一个环节呢
For the first part of making Steamed Chinese Cabbage in Supreme Soup
# 还得先吊汤
You need to make a good broth
# 又吊上汤了 又吊上了
It's broth again
# 先把这个鸡爪子
Remove the chicken feet first
# 不用
We won't use it
# 鸡屁股也不用
Chicken butt neither
# 鸡头我已经砍掉了 鸡头腥
I've cut off the chicken head，it has odor
# 因为咱们在家里做 锅小一点
Because we are using smaller pots at home
# 咱们给它改成块
Let's cut it into pieces
# 这次再重复一下
Let's recap:
# 吊汤是为菜而吊汤
Stock is not a finished product, but rather an ingredient, often a base
# 煲汤是为喝而煲汤
Soup is a final product to be served and consumed directly
# 把这鸡胸肉给提出来 提出来
Pull off the chicken breasts
# 一会咱们要做清汤的
We'll use it to clarify the broth later
# 得用这鸡胸肉 左撕右dun（手字旁屯）啊
So we need this chicken breast
# 这个剔个鸡很简单
It's easy to chop a chicken
# 把这个鸡翅膀就扔到锅里头
Put the chicken wings into the pot
# 把这个鸡胸肉拿下来
Take off the chicken breast and cut it
# 这样呢就给它改改块
into chunks.
# 块改小一点便于烹调
Smaller chunks are easier to cook
# 一会熬汤也快
reducing cooking time
# 这老哥俩
My old pals
# 帅呆了
You guys are so cool
# 酷毙了
Coolest kids on the block
# 这点儿得注意
Pay attention, we need to discard this part
# 这鸡的我们管它叫尖端
We call it "tip"
# 一个是有味
It has bad odor
# 一个是不健康
and is unhealthy
# 对
Yes
# 点火啦，
Ignition
# 凉水下锅
Start with cold water
# 鸡在汤里起的作用是鲜
Chicken stock is more umami
# 搁点肘子或者瘦肉
While adding knuckles and lean pork..
# 它是提香
makes the stock richer
# 这个骨头熬汤非常好
Bones are really good for making stock
# 它里面含钙
It contains calcium
# 而且它熬出这汤香
And it also makes the stock very rich
# 用骨头的这种香味
We want to highlight the of the richness of bones
# 肉骨的这种香味 再加上鸡的鲜味
The savoriness of the bones and the umami of chicken
# 这鸡胸肉为了一会还要清汤么
Since we'll be using the chicken breast as a raft to clarify the broth
# 砸一个鸡燥子
Pound the chicken breast heavily
# 白菜简单
Cabbage is the easy part
# 但是这个汤可要了命了
The broth, on the other hand, is very labor-intensive
# 开水白菜是四川的一个 很有名的菜
Steamed Cabbage in Supreme Soup is a famous dish in Sichuan
# 发明这个菜的师傅
The chef who invented this dish
# 是北京饭店的 叫罗国荣
is Luo Guorong from Beijing Hotel
# 川菜大师
Sichuan cuisine master
# 但是那天客人还想吃白菜
That day, the guest craved a Chinese cabbage dish that
# 还要油要少
uses very little oil
# 味儿还要好吃
but also tastes good
# 这开水白菜一端上来
When they served this dish (literally "Chinese Cabbage in Boiled Water")
# 这客人以为真是开水
The guest thought it was cabbage in literal boiled water
# 但是客人这一吃
But was shocked upon tasting it
# 可不一样了 真香
It was amazing.
# 形如开水
The soup is so clear that it looks like boiled water
# 白菜软烂
Cabbage is super soft
# 这成四川名菜了
So it became a famous Sichuan dish
# 这个鸡蓉砸好了
Chicken breast ('saozi') is ready
# 这有什么用处啊
How we are going to use this
# 一会清汤啊
We use it to clarify the broth
# 鸡蓉不用砸特别细 不用砸太细
Don't need to be too fine-grained
# 让它那筋能连着
It should still be connected by the tendon
# 待会儿下锅清这汤的时候
When clarifying the broth
# 它会把汤里面所有的杂质都吸上去
It will absorb all the impurities in the soup
# 顺手搁两片姜
Now we put two slices of ginger
# 待会再搁两片葱
Two chunks of green onion later
# 就齐啦
That's all.
# 你看见没有
Do you see
# 它为什么凉水下
That is why you should start with cold water
# 它慢慢的把这个脏东西 从里到外给拱出来
This slowly expels the impurities inside the meat into the stock
# 出沫子了啊
Now the scum comes out
# 沫子一定要干净
Let's skim it off
# 要撇净了
all should be skimmed.
# 看着啊沫子起来了
Look at the foam
# 当有时候不好打的时候
Sometimes it's hard to skim
# 下点凉水
just add some cold water
# 要砸一下
To 'smash' it.
# 砸一下以后呢
'Smash'
# 你看
You see
# 这沫子就沉下来点儿来了
The foam sinks after I "smashed" it
# 再逮一逮沫子
And then continue skimming
# 沫子释放的更加充分
The scum is released more fully
# 砸这沫子是为了撇东西
'Smashing' is for skimming
# 我参加过这么多电视节目
I've been on so many TV shows
# 我也看过无数次电视节目
I've seen countless TV shows, too
# 没有一个是真正的 像这么着
None of them are as hardcore as this
# 你看郑老师今天无私的
Chef Zheng is selfless and patient
# 两次了 两次教清汤
Showing us twice how to clarify a stock
# 咱们把出好水的肉 搁另外一个锅里头
Let's move the stock to another pot
# 我们还要坚持
We will insist on
# 我上次说的这个道理
What I said last time
# 还要高压 减少汤的嘌呤
Use pressure cooking to reduce purine level
# 把它弄干净以后
After clarifying it
# 搁到这里头
Put it here
# 骨头再出出水
The bone needs more time
# 这锅有点小
My pot is a little bit small
# 分两次
Need to boil each side
# 家庭版也很重要啊
Home edition also need carefulness
# 跟酒店的整个过程都是一样的
The process is the same as that in hotel
# 有时候有必要呢
Sometimes it is necessary
# 我们还要给它洗一洗
to wash it
# 二伯给打打沫子
Er Bai please skim off the foam
# 非常干净
now it is very clean
# 这个猪肉的飞水就干净了
The pork is ready
# 原汤 给放在这锅里
Pour the cooking liquid into this pot
# 帮我扶一下锅
Help me handle the pot
# 再加点水啊
Add more water
# 给它压上
to submerge the meat
# 不拿高压锅压得多长时间
How long does the pressure cooker takes
# 要照着四小时
Normally stocks take four hours
# 拿高压锅压着 二十五分钟半小时就行
Using pressure cooker it takes only 25-30 minutes
# 让放气儿
Is that so?
# 一个多小时就够了
One hour will suffice, including pressure release
# 这汤你看见没有？ 彻底干净了
See the stock, now is thoroughly clear
# 这时候我们把它高压上
Now we're going to cook with high pressure
# 你看这沫子特别干净
The stock is very clear now
# 看好了啊
Very good.
# 我们把这个放到锅里头
Put it back into the pot
# 煲汤
Stew soup mode
# 二十五分钟 就开始啦
25 minutes to go
# 用四川话说嘞就叫开水白菜
'Boiled Water and Cabbage' (in Sichuan accent)
# 我们做呢应该是找应季的 应季的白菜
We should use cabbages that are in season
# 应该是最好的白菜是产在哪儿呢？ 产在山东泰安
The best Chinese cabbage is produced in Tai'an, Shandong
# 泰安有三美啊
Tai'an has three delicacies
# 白菜
Chinese cabbage
# 豆腐 水
Tofu and spring water
# 它那个白菜叫黄芽白
That cabbage is called Huang Ya Bai
# 叫黄芽菜
or Huang Ya Cai
# 那菜绝了吃完了
It tastes amazing
# 那菜要做出来以后更漂亮
This dish will be more beautiful with Huang Ya Bai
# 金黄金黄的
Golden yellow
# 但是我们今天用的是娃娃菜
But we use baby napa cabbages today
# 娃娃菜在烫的时候多烫一会儿
Baby cabbages should be blanched for a bit longer
# 去掉娃娃菜本身的涩苦味
to remove the bitter taste of it
# 不用搁点盐么
Do you need some salt
# 不用
No
# 这边煮着菜
While it is boiling here
# 咱们取鸡汤
Let's check the chicken broth
# 高压锅吊汤 来着
Making broth with a pressure cooker
# 一锅清汤
Pot filled with clear broth
# 二伯你看这白菜煮的 咕嘟咕嘟的声音
Listen to the sound of cabbage boiling
# 多有气氛
I like this atmosphere
# 看看啊 大家听听这声儿
Listen to this
# 咕嘟咕嘟咕嘟咕嘟
Gudong gudu gudu gudu gudu
# 好啦 白菜已经好了
Now the cabbage is ready
# 关火 好了以后我们去给它冲凉
Then we need to rinse it under cold water
# 大家看看啊
Listen
# 好多人为什么白菜 捂的臭白菜味啊， 它不鲜阿
Why do folks complain that their napa cabbage doesn't taste good?
# 它不冲凉啊有时候
It's because they don't cool it down
# 对
Yes
# 要把这白菜的味彻底冲干净
We need to get rid of this smell
# 趁他不在赶紧尝尝
Let's taste it while he's not here
# 苦不苦啊
Is it still bitter
# 涩也没了吧
or astringent?
# 这一冲啊还真没了
All are gone
# 而且吧正合适
It is just alright
# 凉了我们把它劈开
And then we split it after cooling down
# 一劈四瓣
to quarters
# 我给你说这味道啊
Man I just want to tell you about the flavour
# 一点都没有邪味了
It doesn't contain any weird taste any more
# 把这个心儿口朝上
Let the inner part of cabbage face upward
# 把它修整整齐
Trim it up
# 走
Let't go
# 看看啊看看白菜多整齐
Look how tidy this dish is
# 看看撇油呢啊
Skim the oil.
# 撇油的时候这汤一定要开
This broth must be boiling when you skim the oil
# 这油在上头飘着
The oil is floating
# 有时候一推还往边儿上走
Sometimes you have to push it to the side
# 把油要拾（手四个又）干净
Remove the oil
# 好 还是老师傅心细啊
Well that is carefulness from old chef
# 做活儿讲究
Very crafted work
# 你闻着这汤很香
The broth smells so good
# 到最后油少汤多
At the end, we want less oil and more liquid
# 别浪费这汤
Don't waste the broth
# 来我吹一下 把油吹出去
Blow the oil out
# 好了这汤已经没有油了
Well, there is no oil in this broth
# 这是鸡蓉 鸡蓉用点水把它分解开
Hydrate the pound chicken breast
# 这里边搁点花雕酒
Put some Huadiao Wine in it
# 没花雕酒还真不行
We can't make it without Huadiao Wine
# 花雕
Huadiao wine is really useful
# 还不少搁呢
Huadiao comes
# 这鸡蓉把它抓碎
Stir the chicken
# 这汤已经开了 倒进去
Put it into the boiling broth
# 这时候开大火
Turn the heat to high
# 搅动 一个方向
Stir in one direction
# 马上就开
It will boil soon.
# 蒸锅准备好
Steamer ready
# 因为这白菜要去蒸
Because we are going to steam the cabbage soup
# 这个汤给它扫清了
This is called 'Sao'
# 这叫扫汤
Which makes the soup even more clear
# 一种是白臊
There are to way to 'Sao', one is white Sao
# 所谓白臊就是用鸡胸肉
So called Bai Sao is to use chicken breast
# 还有一种是红臊
Another kind is called red Sao
# 比如说用瘦牛肉啊， 瘦里脊啊
using beef fillet
# 它这汤出来以后颜色比较稍微重一点
Color of our soup seems to be a little bit deep
# 还有一个呢 宫廷里面叫双吊汤
There is another way used by the noble in the past
# 又使牛肉又使鸡肉
Use both beef and chicken
# 你看见没有 它这一开把那油都带出来了
You see, boiling brings oil to the surface
# 你看现在这浮沫已经出来了
Now the foam comes out again
# 有时候我们在熬汤当中 也会出现其他一些现象
Some other phenomenon occurs when we hanging soup
# 有点里面搁了好多肉皮凤爪
Some of them have a lot of meat skin and chicken claws in them
# 关键他搁这些东西 它那胶原蛋白太厚
The problem is these things contains too much collagen
# 他搁了这些比较浑浊的东西
So putting this things
# 它容易浑汤
makes the soup turbid
# 你看这水开了
You see the water is boiling
# 这沫子全都浮起来了
The foam is all floating
# 把这沫子打干净
Clean all these foam
# 现在这汤基本就清了
You're almost done with the soup now
# 为了使这汤更加完美
And then in order to make the soup even more perfect
# 二次砸
'Smash' it fot the second time
# 大火呼一下 顺时针搅动
Set in on high heat and stir
# 通过鸡蓉下去这种
Utilizing the mincered chicken breast
# 搅动 旋转 收缩
do agitation rotation and contraction
# 它把汤里面的一些杂质 基本上都给收起来了
It basically absorbs all the impurities in the soup
# 大家看啊这汤已经清了
The soup is clear
# 这沫子打干净
Clean the foam
# 有点网友在上次节目当中
For our last video
# 提了一些疑问
audience raised some questions
# 什么叫砸呀
What means 'smashing'?
# 今天我给大家演示一下啊
Let me show you today
# 接点凉水
Get some cold water
# 这汤现在可能觉得沫子少了吧
The soup has few foam on its surface
# 可能还有沫子 再砸它一遍
Maybe there are still some foam inside, so 'smash' it
# 看见没有 再砸
Do you see
# 凉水一砸
'smash' using cold water
# 大火一开
The set the fire high.
# 现在已经清澈无比了
It is crystal clear now
# 已经见底儿了把
We can even see bottom of the pot
# 而且这东西往下沉了应该
And the chicken breast sinks
# 你看
You see
# 慢慢慢慢就下去了
It's going down slowly
# 对你看 一会还有沫子
There will be some foam taken out by the mincered chicken later
# 砸呢就是要把它
Smash
# 这鸡蓉里面也有沫子 彻底砸出来
It's just to bring out all the foam, even in the mincered chicken
# 你看啊 这汤更清
You see, it is clearer
# 看着啊 关火
Turn off the fire.
# 关火了大爷
Turn off the fire
# 关火了 过萝
Turn off the fire and filter now
# 最好燉它半小时
we'd better hanging or stewing for half an hour
# 上次咱们讲燉
Next time we talk about stewing
# 燉完了这个料就沉底了
When we done stewing, everything sink to the bottom
# 另外这鸡蓉的香味 也能给它吊出来
In addition, the flavor of mincered chicken can be triggered by hanging
# 你看这鸡蓉已经吊出味了
You see, the flavour of chicken comes out
# 你看这汤颜色
Yes
# 你看砸下去了吧
Look at the soup. The chicken is smashed down
# 颜色也很黄
The color is yellow
# 过滤的时候注意点鸡蓉
Pay attention to mincered chickenwhen filtering
# 鸡蓉也有渣子
There are dregs in it
# 我们别搅动
Do not stir.
# 最好用双层豆包布
Finally, we'd better use double layer Doubao cloth
# 双层豆包布 给它过一下
Double layer Doubao cloth
# 豆包布过完了 还得用纸去粘粘油去
After that, use paper to dip oil
# 过去做宴会最讲究的在这儿呢
In the past, this is the most fastidious detail in banquet
# 汤 齐了
The soup is ready
# 现在开始调味
Now it's time to season
# 搁盐
Salt.
# 白胡椒粉
White pepper powder
# 因为这个汤用的是娃娃菜
Because this soup is made of baby cabbage
# 它可能会有点涩苦味
it might be a little bitter
# 我们在调汤的时候
When we season soup
# 稍微点点糖 点点糖
Put a little sugar
# 好
good
# 这味就有啦
Now we are done
# 这可以把它灌在这里 漂亮
This time pour it on the cabbage
# 开水白菜蒸到什么时候为好呢
When should we stop steaming?
# 白菜浮起 即好
When the cabbage floats
# 这就是窍门 飘起来
When it floats
# 开水白菜
Boiled Chinese Cabbage in Soup!
# 这白菜 我也创点新
I made some innovation
# 中间撒了点枸杞
I put some medlar
# 不错
Pretty good
# 真是开水大白菜
This is really boiled cabbage
# import ending.sbv 0:11:27.600